A Guide to the Papers of John Dos Passos 1865-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Writings (manuscripts, speeches and research)
  - Published works on society, politics, history and travel (Box 22-109)
    - Occasions and Protests (1964) n.d. (Box 80-81)
      Early manuscript drafts, n.d. (4 folders) Later manuscript drafts, n.d. (3 folders) TMs, final version (2 folders)
    - One Man's Initiation--1917 (1920) ca. 1917-1970, n.d. (Box 81)
      Typescript (with Dudley Poore, TLS), ca. 1917, 1970 TMs, First Sight of War, "A Preface Twenty Five Years Later," n.d. Print text, chapter VI of First Encounter, [a reprinted version of OMI, ca. 1945] Reviews, 1920, 1969
    - The Portugal Story (1969) ca. 1968-1969, n.d. (Box 82-87)
      Notes, ca. 1968 (4 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1968 (4 folders) Later manuscript drafts with corrections, ca. 1968-1969 (3 folders) TMs, final version, ca. 1968-1969 (4 folders) TMss, "A Preface to the Portuguese Edition," 1968 Publisher's setting copy, 1968-1969 Galleys and proofs, 1968-1969 (3 folders) Publisher's unused manuscript The Enterprise of the Indies ), n.d. (3 folders) Reviews, 1969
    - The Prospect Before Us (1950) 1940s-1950 (Box 88-90)
      Notes and outlines, 1940s-1950 (2 folders) Early manuscript drafts, 1945-1950 (4 folders) Later manuscript drafts, 1945-1950 (6 folders) Miscellaneous manuscript pages, 1945-1950 (2 folders) TMs, final version, 1945-1950 (2 folders) Publisher's setting copy, 1945-1950 (5 folders) Publisher's uncorrected proof, 1950
    - Prospects of a Golden Age (1959) 1957-ca. 1959, n.d. (Box 91-92)
      Notes, ca. 1958 (2 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1959 (5 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1959 (6 folders) Background data, n.d. Related correspondence, 1957-1958
    - A Pushcart at the Curb (1922) ca.1916-1919, n.d. (Box 93)
      Manuscript drafts with corrections, ca. 1916-1919, n.d. Publisher's setting copy with changes, n.d. Background poetry about Spain, ca. 1916-1919
    - Seven Times Round the Walls of Jericho (unpublished) 1917-1920 (Box 93-94)
      Manuscript drafts, 1917-1918 (2 folders) TMs, final version, 1917-1918 (3 folders) TMs, final version (Robert Hillyer signed copy), 1917-1918 Related correspondence, 1919-1920
    - The Shackles of Power: Three Jeffersonian Decades (1966) 1958-1966, n.d. (Box 95-101)
      Notes and outlines, 1958-1965, n.d. (13 folders) Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1966 (5 folders) Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1966 (5 folders) TMs, randomly arranged, unmarked pages, ca. 1966 (6 folders) Publisher's setting copy, 1966 (6 folders) Publisher's proofs, ca. 1966 (4 folders) Reviews, 1966
    - State of the Nation (1944) ca. 1942-1944 (Box 101-102)
      Notes, ca. 1942-1944 Manuscript drafts, ca. 1942-1944 (6 folders) Miscellaneous manuscript drafts, ca. 1942-1944 Publisher's setting copy, 1944 (2folders) Reviews, 1944
    - Streets of Night (1923) 1922 (Box 103)
      Manuscript drafts, 1922
    - The Theme is Freedom (1956) ca. 1956 (Box 103-104)
      Miscellaneous manuscript drafts, essays and notes, ca. 1956 (5 folders) Final manuscript drafts, ca. 1956 (2 folders)
    - Three Plays: The Garbage Man, Airways, Inc. and Fortune (1934) 1934-1936 (Box 104)
      TMs, Fortune Heights, ca. 1934 (2 folders) Reviews, 1934-1936
    - Three Soldiers (1921) 1921, 1932, n.d. (Box 104)
      Manuscript draft, "Introduction" to Three Soldiers, n.d. TMs drafts of "Preface" to the novel, 1932 Review ("John Dos Passos Lies!" by Norman S. Hall), 1921
    - Thomas Jefferson: The Making of a President (1964) 1964 (Box 104)
      Publisher's setting copy, 1964
    - Tour of Duty (1946) ca. 1942-1946, n.d. (Box 105-107)
      Notes and outlines, including a notebook entitled Berlin 1945, ca. 1944-1945, n.d. (3 folders); Early manuscript drafts, ca. 1944-1945, n.d. (3 folders); Later manuscript drafts, ca. 1944-1945, n.d. (6 folders); Miscellaneous manuscripts not used in final version, ca. 1942-1945, n.d. Publisher's setting copy, 1945 (2 folders); Background relating to WWII Europe and the Pacific, ca. 1942-1946, n.d. (3 folders)
    - U.S.A. (1938) (1. The 42nd Parallel, 2. Nineteen Nineteen, 3. The Big Money ) 1938, ca. 1956, n.d. (Box 108)
      Notes on organization of the trilogy, n.d. Publisher's proofs Reviews, 1938 TS: A Suggested Treatment of the Dos Passos Trilogy: U.S.A., ca. 1956 Notes of dramatic and "proposed" film versions of U.S.A., 1956-1960 (5 folders) Record set: U.S.A. Selections from the 42nd Parallel (See audio T-150)
    - U.S.A.: A Dramatic Revue (1960) (in collaboration with Paul Shyre) ca. 1960, 1971-1983, n.d. (Box 109)
      TMs, with corrections, ca. 1960 (2 folders) TMss, final versions, ca. 1950 (2 folders) Print programs and photo of U.S.A. drama presentations, 1971-1983, n.d.
    - World in a Glass: A View of Our Century (1966) 1965-1966 (Box 109)
      Page proofs, 1965 (2 folders) Reviews, 1966
  - Contributions to books, periodicals and newspapers (Box 110-112)
    - Adlai Stevenson: Patrician with a Mission/ National Review 1956 (Box 110)
    - Against American Literature/ National Review 1916 (Box 110)
    - The American Cause / by Russell Kirk/Foreword / by John Dos Passos 1966 (Box 110)
    - The American Theatre: 1930-1931/ New Republic 1931 (Box 110)
    - Another Plea for Recognition/ New Republic 1934 (Box 110)
    - Antonio Machado: An Introduction/ Eighty Poems of Antonio Machado 1957 (Box 110)
    - Back Home in 1919/ Esquire 1933
      Japanese first edition reprint (1989)
    - Back to Red Hysteria!/ New Republic 1930 (Box 110)
    - The Battle of San Francisco/ National Review 1964 (Box 110)
    - The Bomb / by Frank Harris/Introduction / by John Dos Passos, 1963 (Box 110)
    - Carlos Tresca/ Nation 1943 (Box 110)
    - A Case of Conscience/ Common Sense 1935 (Box 110)
    - The City of Burnished Copper/ Choate News, Fiction Supplement 1911 (Box 110)
    - The Communist Party and the War Spirit/ Common Sense 1937 (Box 110)
    - The Death of James Dean/ Esquire 1958 (Box 110)
      reprint edition (1973)
    - The Death of José Robles/ New Republic 1939 (Box 110)
    - Did the New Playwrights Theatre Fail[?]/ New Masses 1929 (Box 110)
    - Everybody Knows the Mayor/ Liberty 1945 (Box 110)
    - The Failure of Marxism/ Life 1945 (Box 110)
    - Farewell to Europe/ Common Sense 1937 (Box 111)
    - Faulkner/ National Review 1963 (Box 111)
    - First Love/ Harvard Monthly 1915 (Box 111)
    - From "Simonides" (poem)/ Harvard Monthly 1916 (Box 111)
    - The General/ The Modern Millwheel 1950, 2 folders (Box 111)
    - Have You Thought of the Immigrants/ Common Sense 1936 (Box 111)
    - A Humble Protest/ Harvard Monthly 1916 (Box 111)
    - In Defense of Kentucky/ New Republic 1931 (Box 111)
    - Lendas da India / by Gaspar Correa/ New York Times book review 1969 (Box 111)
    - Les Lauriers Sont Coupés Harvard Monthly 1916 (Box 111)
    - Lese Majeste/ New Masses 1927 (Box 111)
    - Lines to a Lady (poem)/ The American Caravan 1927 (Box 111)
    - The Living Thoughts of Tom Paine/ Living Thoughts Library 1940 (Box 111)
    - A Memory (poem)/ Eight Harvard Poets 1917 (Box 111)
    - Metropolis (poem) / by Manuel Maples Arce/Trans. / by John Dos Passos 1929 (Box 111)
    - Mr. Dos Passos on "Him"/ New York Times 1928 (Box 111)
    - The New Masses I'd Like/ New Masses 1926 (Box 111)
    - Night-Piece (poem)/ Harvard Monthly 1916 (Box 111)
    - 1968/ National Review 1968 (Box 111)
    - On The Way To A Moon Landing/ U.S. Information Service ca. 1969 (Box 111)
    - Paint the Revolution!/ New Masses 1927 (Box 112)
    - Panama / by Blaise Cendrars/Trans. and Illus. / by John Dos Passos 1931 (Box 112)
    - Please, Mr. Rip Van Winkle, Wake Up Some More/ National Review 1964 (Box 112)
    - "Prairies" (poem)/ Harvard Monthly 1915
      his first published poem
    - A Question of Elbow Room/ Essays in Individuality 1958 (Box 112)
    - Refugees Still Suffering (letter to the editor)/ New York Times 1940 (Box 112)
    - Response to Orville C. Pratt's letter/ New Republic 1936 (Box 112)
    - Satire As a Way of Seeing (intro. / by John Dos Passos)/ Interregnum / by Geo. Grosz 1937 (Box 112)
    - Science Under Siege/ NY Herald Tribune 1952 (Box 112)
    - The Shepherd/ Harvard Monthly 1916 (Box 112)
    - Snarling Diplomats (book review)/ New Masses 1926 (Box 112)
    - The Spaniards Were Here Before Us/ Reader's Digest 1957 (Box 112)
    - Ten Days in the Ice Age/ Holiday 1966 (Box 112)
    - Thank You Mr. Hitler!/ Common Sense 1933 (Box 112)
    - Towards a Revolutionary Theatre/ New Masses 1927 (Box 112)
    - 23 Juin 1415: Objectif Ceuta/un recit historique de John Dos Passo n.d. (Box 112)
    - Two Eighteenth-Century Careers/ New Republic 1939 (Box 112)
    - U.S.A. Revisited/ New York Times 1958 (Box 112)
    - Wanted: An Ivy Lee for Liberals (letter to the editor)/ New Republic 1930 (Box 112)
    - Washington is the Loneliest City n.d. (Box 112)
    - What Can We Offer the World?/ Spadea Sydicate 1954 (Box 112)
    - What Chances of Maintaining a Conservative Opposition?/ National Review 1964 (Box 112)
    - Where Do We Go from Here?/ Life 1947 (Box 112)
    - The Writer as Technician/ American Writers Congress 1935 (Box 112)
  - Prose and verse of undetermined publication (Box 113-118)
    - ... and graceful steps arousing admiration... (portion) 1914 (Box 113)
    - A man is shot down the street in New York... (Box 113)
    - A meadow of tall grass filled with daisies... (Box 113)
    - A single shaded light shows... (play re: Williams, Tom and Kitty) (Box 113)
    - Adventures About An Orchard (English 12 theme) (Box 113)
    - After Passing of Conscription (poem) 1917, n.d. (Box 113)
    - Afterglow (Box 113)
    - An Unreconstructed Jeffersonian (Box 113)
    - The Arab was better than his word (Box 113)
    - The Architecture of the White House (Box 113)
    - Art and Aspiration (Art and Baseball) (Box 113)
    - As the literal-minded young men of the FBI have occasionally reminded me... (Box 113)
    - August Twilight (poem) (Box 113)
    - Back in Washington I went around to see a labor statistician... (Box 113)
    - Barcelona of the Bombs 1919, n.d.
    - The Beginning of the Contemporary Chronicles (Box 113)
    - Blck, blotched with faces of men... 1918, n.d. (Box 113)
    - Blueprint for the future (Box 113)
    - Born in Chicago in the year McKinley was elected... [autobiographical draft] (Box 113)
    - Brazil by Willys, Houseboat and Taxi Plane, 2 folders (Box 113)
    - Bryan (Box 113)
    - Bubbles and the Sea-Wind (poem) (Box 113)
    - Can't I fly up to you, oh golden moon... (poem) (Box 113)
    - Chicago's Morning Colonel (Box 113)
    - City Twilight (poem--English 5, weekly theme) (Box 113)
    - The Classical Tradition in English Literature, 2 folders (Box 114)
    - Conversations in Italy (Box 114)
    - Could I but still my doubt... (poem--on verso of Wright McCormick ALS) (Box 114)
    - A Country Lawyer Come[?] to Town (Box 114)
    - Country Road (poem) (Box 114)
    - Dead Failure (poem) (Box 114)
    - Debs was a railroad man (Box 114)
    - Discurso Inaugural 1962 (Box 114)
    - England Under Labor 1947, n.d. (Box 114)
    - The Established Order (Box 114)
    - Ever since... I started to do some research on... Tom Paine's writing (Box 114)
    - The Fall of Aaron Burr ca. 1964, 6 folders (Box 114)
    - First aid instructions (Box 115)
    - The Formative Decade (Box 115)
    - Fragments d'une Enfance Bruxelloise (Box 115)
    - Freedom and the Writer (Box 115)
    - The Future of Socialism (Box 115)
    - Genre (poem) (Box 115)
    - The Great Conspiracy (Box 115)
    - The Great Depression (Box 115)
    - Grotesque (poem) ca. 1917-1925 (Box 115)
    - Guipuzcoa 1923 (Box 115)
    - Hans Christian Goldwyn (Box 115)
    - The Hedgehog of the Middle East (Box 115)
    - How hard it is to write truthfully (Box 115)
    - I arise from dreams of anisette... (poem) (Box 115)
    - If a foreigner should ask me what Americans were like in 1946... (Box 115)
    - Ike Hall (Box 115)
    - Ils m'ont graissée avec des onguents... (Box 115)
    - In dusk dark figures move... (poem) (Box 115)
    - In Madrid the picture was fairly simple (Box 115)
    - Introduction to [_?_] Anthology (Box 115)
    - Introductory: Sinbad was in bad.. ., 1968 (Box 115)
    - It was a very humbling experience... (Box 115)
    - It is largely because you proved yourself a conscientious liberal (Box 115)
    - It is tragic that Scott Fitzgerald did not live to finish The Last Tycoon (Box 115)
    - It was puzzlement more than disillusionment I suffered from (Box 115)
    - It was somewhere during years of the early New Deal... (Box 115)
    - It's a trite old saying that we never know when we are well off (Box 115)
    - It's almost thirty years since I first knew Spain (Box 115)
    - Japan, for a hundred years now... (Box 115)
    - Ladies Orchestra (poem) (Box 115)
    - The Land Where the Rockfish Rules (with snapshots of John Dos Passos) (Box 115)
    - Little Green Frogs (Box 115)
    - Madeira (English 12 Composition) 1915 (Box 115)
    - The Marines takeover Internal Revenue (Box 115)
    - Meditation on the Great Tradition (Box 115)
    - Memo from DP to DP, Re: "Take the Cheese Away from the Table" (Box 115)
    - Minstrels (poem) (Box 115)
    - Moon-Struck (poem) (Box 115)
    - The Moth (poem) (Box 115)
    - Mr. Hervey Meaghan, the Mayor explained the city's program... (Box 116)
    - Mr. Roosevelt's Crusade (Box 116)
    - My Mother was a Lady (poem) (Box 116)
    - My name is James Carey... (Box 116)
    - Nectarines (revised) (Box 116)
    - Nectarines and Boulogne-sur-Mer (Box 116)
    - Nettlefire (poem) ca. 1917-1925 (Box 116)
    - Nobody can ever forget their first reading of Dostoevski... (Box 116)
    - Not long ago I received a letter from some German students... (Box 116)
    - A Note on Fitzgerald (Box 116)
    - The Novel as Chronicle (Box 116)
    - The Novelist Talks About History (Box 116)
    - Old Danielson... a corresponding member of the British Israel Society... (Box 116)
    - The Old Order (poem) (Box 116)
    - On one of the barges... (poem) ca. 1918 (Box 116)
    - On Reading of the Death of Debussy (poem), ca. 1918 (Box 116)
    - One Man Has the Nerve (Box 116)
    - One of the advantages of surviving for a few years.. ., ca. 1955 (Box 116)
    - Our little expedition wasn't without comic relief (Box 116)
    - The Past (poem) ca. 1917-1925 (Box 116)
    - A Pastoral (Box 116)
    - Perhaps the next most vivid recollection is of swimming lessons... (Box 116)
    - Pictures to Look At/A Manhattan Primitive ca. 1917-1925 (Box 116)
    - Preface to the English Edition: The first book I ever wrote (Box 116)
    - Project outline for a possible libertarian pamphlet (Box 116)
    - Retrospect--1932 (V) (Box 116)
    - Richard Aldington (Box 116)
    - The Sack of Corinth ca. 1917-1925 (Box 116)
    - The Sacred Streets of Baltimore (Box 116)
    - Santa Theresa (Box 116)
    - The Shop Window (poem) (Box 116)
    - The Smile on the Face of the Tiger ca. 1917-1925 (Box 116)
    - Sometime after we had all left Harlan County... (Box 116)
    - Sonnet (poem--English 5 theme) (Box 116)
    - Sonnet (poem) (Box 116)
    - Spanish Tragedy (Box 116)
    - Spoiled Workers (Box 116)
    - Stories of Ramon Ferriere (Box 116)
    - Summer Rain (poem) (Box 116)
    - Sunrise (poem) (Box 116)
    - That Garden of Sedate Philosophy (poem) (Box 116)
    - The Armory Show was a real jolt... (Box 116)
    - The house was still, smelt of coal oil... (poem) (Box 116)
    - The only time I met the man... (Box 116)
    - The is Opossum's Other Book (Box 116)
    - This was in December, 1937 though I saw it dimly... (Box 116)
    - To relieve monotony of a work on one subject, we will extract from a diary... (Box 116)
    - To _______ (poem) (Box 116)
    - Trains, Fragments of Memories (English 12 Composition VI) 1914 (Box 116)
    - The Trials of Louise (Box 116)
    - The Truth about Visual Training 1941-1975, n.d. (Box 116)
    - The Ultimate Victory of Aunt Ella ca. 1917-1925 (Box 117)
    - Untitled Screenplay [produced as The Devil is a Woman with Marlene Dietrich] (1934) (Box 117)
    - The Use of the Past (Box 117)
    - We live in the golden age of print (Box 117)
    - When I spent a couple of months in Madrid... (Box 117)
    - When I started Manhattan Transfer thirty or more years ago my aim was... (Box 117)
    - The World is a golden orchard... (poem) (Box 117)
    - The Wreck of the Marie Celeste (poem) (Box 117)
  - Prose and verse of undetermined authorship and publication (Box 117)
    - The Altruist ca. 1917-1925 (Box 117)
    - Cecelia and Chorus (poem) [portion] (Box 117)
    - Crescent Moon (poem) (Box 117)
    - Debs was a railroad man... (Box 117)
    - Hill-Top Pasture (poem) (Box 117)
    - How you are gone when I can say... (poem) (Box 117)
    - I was sitting in a little house... (poem) (Box 117)
    - La Estrella de Sevilla (unsigned play) (Box 117)
    - Largo (Box 117)
    - Marietta-August (poem) (Box 117)
    - Nip and Tuck/A Black Song and Dance (Box 117)
    - The Philosopher (poem) (Box 117)
    - Places in France (poems) (Box 117)
    - Release (poem) (Box 117)
    - Revolution ca. 1917-1925 (Box 117)
    - Scene: A salon in a fashionable pension in Paris... (untitled play) (Box 117)
    - Sever Eleven[?] (poem) (Box 117)
    - Sonnet (poem)/(verso)/A Farewell (poem) [with print poem: Sonnet / by Wm. A. Norris] (Box 117)
    - Sonnet XL /&/ To a Scarlatti Passepied (poems) / by Robt. Silliman Hillyer 1916, n.d. (Box 117)
    - War (poem) (Box 117)
  - Speech material (Box 117-118)
    - About Brazil (various) 1958-1963 (Box 117)
    - National Review (10th anniversary dinner) 1965 (Box 117)
    - NBC-TV (panelist) 1962 (Box 117)
    - Pavlovian Laboratory ("Objective Description") 1955 (Box 117)
    - Pavlovian Society (Box 117)
    - Portuguese Union n.d. (Box 117)
    - Princeton University 1957 (Box 118)
    - Readings of his published works n.d., 2 folders (Box 118)
    - San Jose State College (convocation address) 1964 (Box 118)
    - University of Virginia (on Jefferson) 1957 (Box 118)
    - Untitled speech drafts n.d. (Box 118)
    - Washington and Lee University (on journalism) ca. 1952 (Box 118)
  - Research and background (Box 118-121)
    - American and English history n.d., 3 folders (Box 118)
    - Jefferson and the Jeffersonian Era n.d., 7 folders (Box 119)
    - Italy n.d. (Box 119)
    - Labor union issues 1929-1960 (Box 119)
    - Newspaper captions 1914-1922, n.d. (Box 120)
    - 1930s-1940s, 3 folders (Box 120)
    - Russia/USSR 1929-1936, n.d. (Box 120)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks n.d., 3 folders (Box 120-121)
    - Loose drafts and notes n.d., 4 folders (Box 121)
  Series III
- Personal (Box 122-139)
  - Artwork by John Dos Passos (Box 122)
    - Catalogues of John Dos Passos' art showings 1960-1981 (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketch (color imposed on photograph)/jeep driving over a hill n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketch/"Clowns" n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketches (untitled)/figures and faces n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketches (untitled)/roof lines, trees and steeple peak n.d. (Box 122)
    - Photographic prints/of Dos Passos' sketch and watercolor art n.d. (Box 122)
    - Watercolor (1998 Christmas card color print)/"Feria Seville" 1923 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor (Esquire magazine color print)/"Port of New York" 1933 (Box 122)
  - Artwork collected by John Dos Passos (Box 122)
    - Cachet (color printed)/"Bird's Eye View of Alexandria, Va." n.d. (Box 122)
    - Card (color printed)/Pierre L'ermite Prêchant Première Croisade 1903 (Box 122)
    - Caricature (newsprint)/John Randolph Dos Passos (father) n.d. (Box 122)
    - Color printed copies (6)/canines / by Meakin [Louisa "Auntie Lou" Meakin?] n.d. (Box 122)
    - Drawing (untitled copy)/young woman with head resting on hand / by [?] n.d. (Box 122)
    - Drawing (untitled copy)/young woman's head / by Jerry Farnsworth 1957 (Box 122)
    - Drawing/Menemsha House-- / by Adolf Dehn n.d. (Box 122)
    - Drawings/"Mooring designed for John Dos Passo" / by C. Waugh (Box 122)
    - Music record collection listing (Box 122)
    - Music sheet/Cinq M໩lodies--by Wells Hivley 1930 (Box 122)
    - Music audio tape (untitled)/martial and Latin music n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pen-and-ink caricature/of Dos Passos/from André Deutsch and Nicozas Bentley (Box 122)
    - Pen-and-ink sketch (untitled, unsigned)/farm worker n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pen-and-ink sketch/"darcelona 1951" / by Vlady [Vladimir Orloff] 1951 (Box 122)
    - Pen-and-ink sketches (4)/bullfighters, bulls and horses / by Jose Robles 1913 (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketch (unsigned)/man in repose n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketch (untitled and unsigned)/building lines and tree n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketch (untitled and unsigned)/nude n.d. (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketches (untitled)/man behind bars / by Quintanilla/and felines/(unsigned) (Box 122)
    - Pencil sketches/(unsigned) "Cathedral-Lausanne" and "Loggia degli Ozii Milano" (Box 122)
    - Photographic prints (2)/of Diego Rivera's art 1927, n.d. (Box 122)
    - Photographic prints (4)/(untitled, unsigned), museum murals, equine, Venus images (Box 122)
    - Photographic prints (4)/of José Clemente Orozeo's art 1925-1927, n.d. (Box 122)
    - Print/Asia map n.d. (Box 122)
    - Prints/desert scenery-- / by Jean Lurçat (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled printed copy)/moored sailboats / by E.B. Antiveysen (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/Christmas tree trimming frolic--/Ward[?] Gaylor (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/church view through window-- / by Jerry Farnsworth (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/dancing couple-- / by M. Gimene 1962 (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/man and woman sitting by kettle / by Glinten Kamp 1927 (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/man sitting in jail cell-- / by Luis Quintanilla 1934 (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/nude woman reclining-- / by Milton Horn 1932 (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/nude, castle and horseman-- / by Antonio Gattorno n.d. (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/man pointing to obese diner-- / by George Grosz 1938 (Box 122)
    - Sketch (untitled)/village scene-- / by Feliz Sirera 1962 (Box 122)
    - Sketch/John Dos Passos portrait-- / by Willam Johnson L'Engle 1946 (Box 122)
    - Sketch/Le Quartier Latin Paris-- / by Harry Leroy Taskey 1930 (Box 122)
    - Sketch/The Vagrant-- / by Benton M. Spruance 1938 (Box 122)
    - Sketch/Trial Proof-- / by Edwin [Burdett] Tunis n.d. (Box 122)
    - Watercolor (untitled)/bullfighting arena-- / by Paul Garfunkel n.d. (Box 122)
    - Watercolor (untitled)/man standing by a seated woman-- / by R. Hover[?] (Box 122)
    - Watercolor (untitled)/whiskey advertisement-- / by C. Waugh 1933 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor (untitled, unsigned)/elegant woman (Box 122)
    - Watercolor/Accidente Nocturno-- / by Quinquela Martin 1962 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor/Bulls at Pamplona, and Bull stampede-- / by Paul Garfunkel 1958 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor/Images of Brazil-- / by Paul Garfunkel 1958 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor/La Katey Key West-- / by Waldo Peirce 1929 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor/Lazarus shows sores to the handmaidens / by Paul Garfunkel (Box 122)
    - Watercolor/Little Katey in dry dock, Key West / by Waldo Peirce 1929 (Box 122)
    - Watercolor and crayon drawing (untitled, unsigned)/birds in a tree n.d. (Box 122)
    - Watercolor printed copies (8) (untitled, unsigned)/Arabic scenes (Box 122)
    - Watercolor printed copy (unsigned)/dockside dining view (Box 122)
    - Watercolor sketches (2) (untitled)/felines / by Juanita (Box 122)
  - Awards (Box 122-125)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences 1947 (Box 122)
    - Center Stage ( U.S.A. award) 1964 (Box 122)
    - Choate School (Alumni Seal Prize) 1965 (Box 122)